<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-05-26T16:19:07+10:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Damian Testa’s personal site</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Future projects</title><link href="/blog/2021/05/26/future-projects.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Future projects" /><published>2021-05-26T15:48:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-26T15:48:00+10:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/05/26/future-projects</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/05/26/future-projects.html">&lt;p&gt;I want to keep a list of all the things I would like to do but haven’t
done yet. As I do these things, I will link them to their articles in
Projects. These are not in any particular order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ceramics, particularly for use as crockery&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mycoculture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simple electrical work such as installing LED lighting in a piece&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Woodworking (esp. furniture)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Metalworking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laurenceking.com/blog/2019/09/26/dorodango-blog/&quot;&gt;Dorodango&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Automated self-sufficient farming&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Indoor aquaponics to grow fish &amp;amp; vegetables&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resin casting for use in woodwork or simply art&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mixology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">I want to keep a list of all the things I would like to do but haven’t done yet. As I do these things, I will link them to their articles in Projects. These are not in any particular order.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First post</title><link href="/blog/2021/05/26/first-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First post" /><published>2021-05-26T14:16:04+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-26T14:16:04+10:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/05/26/first-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/05/26/first-post.html">&lt;p&gt;Hello! This is my first post on my new site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I built this site as one of my projects; some time ago I built and hosted my own
website on a Raspberry Pi Zero W that I bought for fun one day. However, I
changed my ISP and since then my home IP has been non-static, and I’m too cheap
to pay for hosting (haha), so since then my domain has just been for my email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll seems very cool and relatively simple to use, although I’m still trying
to understand how all the pieces fit together. It’s certainly much easier than
the full LAMP stack I was using before. It’s worth noting that I have no
training as a web dev, I just muck around and find things out myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I intend to host this on Github
which ought to make future blog posts easy (just commit and push a new file),
but I don’t know if I can use my own domain for it. I hear you can, but haven’t
looked into it yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of the motivation for making a blogging platform is that there are a lot of
things that other people do as hobbies that are super interesting to me; however
, as I said on the landing page, I consider myself to be a super generalist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think of myself in terms of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pareto_principle&quot;&gt;Pareto Principle&lt;/a&gt;, which in general
states that for any cause-and-effect relationship, 20% of the causes result in
80% of the effects. In the case of learning new things, 80% of the outcome can
be achieved by the first 20% of the effort; the remaining 80% of the effort
goes into the final 20% of the result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that I’m significantly better at the first 20% than the last 80%, and
would rather be 80% good at 5 things than 100% good at 1 thing anyway. As a
result, I like to dip my toes into lots of stuff, and want to use this as a
place to catalogue the toe-dipping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s possible that I’ll need a more deep directory structure for my projects,
or perhaps a search box. I’ll use the Jekyll tag feature for now and hope that
in future, if I don’t find a way to leverage it, I can just script something
clumsily myself to do the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, that’s all for this one; I will go make a couple of posts for my old projects
now (which I expect to be brief as they’re post-hoc).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="blog" /><category term="meta" /><summary type="html">Hello! This is my first post on my new site.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Music production</title><link href="/project/2021/05/01/music.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Music production" /><published>2021-05-01T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-01T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>/project/2021/05/01/music</id><content type="html" xml:base="/project/2021/05/01/music.html">&lt;p&gt;I find generally that the world of music is really opaque to me. Talking to
people, they almost all have this kind of formative experience during their
teenage years where they discover some band or genre of music that helps
shape their developing personality and informs at least part of their 
direction.&lt;br /&gt;
Personally I never had such an experience; when I was a teenager, most of
the music I knew was written by Weird Al. I liked it because I thought it
was clever. Even now I have a passionate love for mashups like those from
&lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/neilcic/mouthdreams&quot;&gt;Neil Cicierega&lt;/a&gt; that doesn’t seem to be shared by others.&lt;br /&gt;
As a result, I never really got into any particular genres of music. Most
of the popular music I knew and still know is either from a Guitar Hero
setlist or from one of my parents (and hence my love of ’80s rock and pop).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my burgeoning adulthood, I still find that others get more from music
than I do. Melbourne, the city where I live, is renowned for its independent
music and arts scene, but going to performances with my friends often leaves
me feeling unsatisfied in the same way that eating a bowl of white rice
or potato chips does. I see other people dancing and wonder why they feel
the need to. This is probably just me being awkward but I genuinely don’t
get it, even if my reaction is performative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To that end, I’ve made a conscious effort to try to produce my own music.
I hope this will give me a better understanding of what other people like
about music and help me discover more of it. In particular, I like electronic
music of the “lo-fi beats to chill/study/relax to” form, but also more upbeat
music that imparts feelings of certain places or experiences. I really like
&lt;a href=&quot;https://poolside.fm/&quot;&gt;poolside.fm&lt;/a&gt; for example, it makes me feel happy and is good
background noise for a social event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have already produced 3 songs at time of writing; I will probably upload
them somewhere under my own name unless and until I find a style that feels
unique, at which point I will label it with something I feel captures what
I’m going for. I will edit this post with links to the music when I have
uploaded it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="project" /><summary type="html">I find generally that the world of music is really opaque to me. Talking to people, they almost all have this kind of formative experience during their teenage years where they discover some band or genre of music that helps shape their developing personality and informs at least part of their direction. Personally I never had such an experience; when I was a teenager, most of the music I knew was written by Weird Al. I liked it because I thought it was clever. Even now I have a passionate love for mashups like those from Neil Cicierega that doesn’t seem to be shared by others. As a result, I never really got into any particular genres of music. Most of the popular music I knew and still know is either from a Guitar Hero setlist or from one of my parents (and hence my love of ’80s rock and pop).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sailing lessons</title><link href="/project/post-hoc/2019/11/07/sailing-lessons.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sailing lessons" /><published>2019-11-07T01:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2019-11-07T01:00:00+11:00</updated><id>/project/post-hoc/2019/11/07/sailing-lessons</id><content type="html" xml:base="/project/post-hoc/2019/11/07/sailing-lessons.html">&lt;p&gt;In late 2019 I took a beginner’s sailing course. The course was designed
to teach adults to sail dinghies in pairs by teaching introductory sailing
techniques, parts of the boat, ropework, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have this romantic idea of taking my boat out onto the water and having
a relaxing day on the ocean eating a picnic lunch or reading a book etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think in hindsight this is a bit unrealistic; for a start, any keelboat
big enough to have a relatively stable deck seems to require several crew.
&lt;br /&gt;
Secondly, a sailboat has a lot of moving parts that are complex and require
specific domain knowledge. It’s not like a powerboat where you can just hop
in and push the accelerator to go.
&lt;br /&gt;
Finally, sailing scales exponentially in price as the boat gets larger,
so I’m not sure I’ll be able to afford it. I’ve heard it said that “a boat
is a hole in the water that you throw money into” and I don’t find that
prospect very appealing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I end up living somewhere with a healthy community sailing club, I might
pick it up again. I don’t think I’ve retained much from my lessons but
the experience was certainly valuable.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="project" /><category term="post-hoc" /><summary type="html">In late 2019 I took a beginner’s sailing course. The course was designed to teach adults to sail dinghies in pairs by teaching introductory sailing techniques, parts of the boat, ropework, etc.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Painting lessons</title><link href="/project/2018/01/25/painting-lessons.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Painting lessons" /><published>2018-01-25T01:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2018-01-25T01:00:00+11:00</updated><id>/project/2018/01/25/painting-lessons</id><content type="html" xml:base="/project/2018/01/25/painting-lessons.html">&lt;p&gt;In 2018 I took painting lessons in the hopes that it would help me
understand the basics of painting (light/shadow, colour, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had previously taken a course at university called &lt;a href=&quot;https://handbook.unimelb.edu.au/2017/subjects/opto20004&quot;&gt;“Perceptions,
Illusions and Art”&lt;/a&gt;, which was about how artists use painting
techniques to trick the eye into perceiving properties inherent to
binocular vision such as depth, shadow, transparency, etc. on what is
in effect a 2d plane (i.e. a canvas).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was hoping that this course would help me apply some of those techniques
as a beginner painter. However I found the lessons to be quite loose and
freeform, and not as technical as I had hoped. As a result I didn’t feel
that I got too much out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Painting in general is something I find frustrating; it’s not obvious to
me why I can observe things in an image but am unable to replicate it
on a canvas. I think it’s just practice, but practicing things I’m bad at
is a frustrating process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will definitely do more painting in future,
but right now I feel that I have to be in a particular mood to be able
to make progress with it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="project" /><category term="project" /><category term="post-hoc" /><summary type="html">In 2018 I took painting lessons in the hopes that it would help me understand the basics of painting (light/shadow, colour, etc.).</summary></entry></feed>